实习医生格蕾  前情提要
Previously on "Grey's Anatomy"
外科培训记录
The surgical training protocol
非常正式的改变了人们
Is officially changing people.
你觉得你在我面前维护你男友
You thought that you'd defend your boyfriend to me
-我就会对他好些?  -他不是我男友
And i'd just take it? He's not my boyfriend.
你和德里克不行的  为什么你那么在乎我的看法?
You and derek will not work. Why do you care what i think?
如果我真的要搬去和他住  我需要你的支持
If i'm gonna do this with him i need you to cheer me on.
作为外科医生
As surgeons
我们被授予修复的能力
We are trained to fix what's broken.
我有事  不能再待了
I'm in a hurry.I can't stay.
主任要开一个大会
The chief's having a big meeting.
所以我要告诉你  我觉得我不需要心理咨询了
but i wanted to tell you that i'm finished with therapy.
伤口就是我们的起跑线  工作的起跑线
The breaking point is our starting line... At work.
梅丽迪斯  你还需要继续做咨询
Meredith you are not finished.
你在做咨询的时候表现非常好
You have worked Incredibly hard.
看看  你是怎么走过来的
Look how far you've come.
但是你只是触及到了表层
But you're just Scratching the surface.
这样的  德里克搬过来了
Well derek's moved in
我们关系更进了一步
And we've taken it to the next level
这不是德里克的问题
It's not about derek.
-我很幸福
-I'm happy
你还没有完成
You're not done.
-我幸福不是最重要的?  -不是
-I am happy, isn't that the point? -No.
但是在我们的生活中
But in our lives
伤口就是虚弱的表现
The breaking point is a sign of weakness...
-我需要你坐下来接着治疗
I need you to stay for the session.
-我  不行  要开会了  主任的会
I no The meeting The chief i...
谢谢你怀亚特医生
Thank you Dr. Wyatt.
感谢你所做的一切
Thanks for everything.
当然我们会尽可能的避免伤口
And we'll do everything we can to avoid it.
-抱歉  -你在这儿做什么?
-sorry. -What are you doing in here?
我计划在你搬走之后把这改造成办公室
I'm thinking about making this my office when you move out.
当我搬走?  我什么时候搬走?
When i move out?When am i moving out?
近期?
Soon?
你知道梅丽迪斯盘算着把我们赶出去吗?
Did you know meredith was planning on making us move out?
-伊兹  我正忙  -如果你愿意你也可以参加
I'm kinda busy here iz.-You can join us if you want.
不!
No!
你打算什么时候才跟我们关照  我们该滚蛋了
When were you planning on telling us we had to move out?
你打算什么时候告诉他们该搬走了
When were you planning on telling them they had to move out?
什么?  为什么他们要搬走?
What? Why do they have to move out?
梅丽迪斯看我为你特制的
Meredith hey look I made this especially for you.
家像个公园  或者阿历克斯和他闪亮女人们的乌托邦
It's a zoo a frat house with alex and his parade of women
他那些闪亮的婊子们
His parade of skanks.
不管怎么说  我现在该开始找房子了吗?
Whatever. Am i apartment hunting or what?
我不知道  我要想想看
I don't know. I have to think about it.
你只消吃吃松饼就可以了  梅丽
Well just you know eat the muffin mer.
尝尝松饼  记得尝尝那松饼
Taste the muffin.Remember the muffin.
我喜欢我的室友们
I like my roommates.
我也喜欢  但那是你以前的生活
I like them too.That was your life.
现在则是我们的生活
This is our life.
而且我感到非常兴奋  因为我们生活在一起
And i'm excited about Building our life together.
拜托了  那一定会很棒的
Come on.It's gonna be great.
德里克想要阿历克斯和伊兹都搬走
So derek wants Alex and izzie to move out.
什么时候你对他开始言听计从的?
Well since when does he say "jump" and you jump?
我很幸福
Well i'm happy.
而我会不满
I'd be pissed off...
你想怎样就怎样吧
But do whatever you want.
你对新规定有没有什么消息?
Hey you hear anything about what the new rules are?
最新的消息是  你和她手牵手
Last i heard you were at hand holding
还有多次促膝夜谈
Foot rubs and lots of Late-night gab sessions.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
各位注意听
Listen up everyone.
不会吧 你是在说主任的新规定
No you were talking about the chief's new rules.
我还以为你指的是你和托蕾丝
I thought you were referring to you and torres.
-注意  -我刚才搞错了
-Listen up.-I've been wrong before.
大家都很忙 所以我长话短说
We're busy people So i'm gonna try and be brief.
我现在要执行一个新规定
I am implementing
是关于西雅图圣恩医院的教学程序的
A new teaching protocol here at seattle grace.
有些规定是新出台
Now some of these rules are new
有些是老的但是要重新强化下
And some are old and are going to be newly enforced.
杰克 欧布林 47岁
Jack o'brien   47
因为腹主动脉瘤住院
Scheduled for an abdominal aortic aneurysm repair.
最新的CT显示他有钙化现象
His last c.t.showed calcification
所以我预约一个CT血管造影来确定肿瘤
So i ordered a c.t. angio to determine
是否恶化或者还是保持稳定
Whether it had worsened or remained stable.
干得好  杨  查房过后你就带他去做
Nice catch yang. You can take him down after rounds.
克莱夫医生来接手这里  杨医生你的工作结束了
Dr. Karev will take over.Dr. Yang you're done here.
谢谢
Thank you.
第一年  第二年  还有第三年的住院医生
First second ad third-year residents
将不会再准许从事临床研究工作
Will no longer be allowed to defacto specialize.
从而进行一个全面的
The practice interferes with the development of
外科知识培训  就这些
A fully rounded surgical education. No more.
巴里 派特莫   63岁
Barry patmore 63
他患有剧烈的头疼
Has been experiencing chronic headaches
长达7年之久
For the past seven years
曾经服用过强副作用的抗癫痫药
Has been treated with narcotics antiseizure medications
抗抑郁药和抗精神病药物
Antidepressants and antipsychotic medications
-都不见起色  -帕特莫先生  今天头疼的厉害吗?
-With no success.-How severe is the pain today mr. Patmore
-尺度是1级到10级  -8级
-Scale of one to ten?  -Eight.
一直都是8级
It's always an eight.
这就是为什么在对Patmore先生最后一次会诊中
Which is why mr. Patmore's Last consult
我们建议采取双面扣带回切开术
Suggested a bilateral cingulotomy
不好意思  用前脑叶白质切除术来治疗头痛?
I'm sorry a frontal lobotomy for a headache?
太吵了
Too loud.
拜托
Please.
能别让这嗡嗡声来烦我吗?
And could you do something about the buzzing?
这些机器都必须要吗?
Do we need all these machines?
帕特莫先生一直备受疼痛的煎熬
Mr. Patmore has been experiencing intense pain
7年当中的每一天都没有停止过
All day every day for seven years.
但是扣带回切开术可能引起癫痫
But the cingulotomy could cause seizures
认知障碍或者是行为异常
Or cognitive defects or behavioral changes.
这就是为什么我们需要
Which is why we are going to explore
在采取这种极端的手术开始之前
Every other possible option before resorting
发现所有可能的情况
to such a radical surgery.
-再做检查  -好的
-More tests.-Yes.
谢博德医生  今天杨医生是你的助手
Dr.Yang you'll be assisting Dr.Shepherd today.
私人关系
Personal relationships
个人贞操还有个人喜好
Personal loyalties and personal favorites
都不会成为培训计划的涵盖范围
Will no longer be a factor in our training program.
注意  你们需要
Attendings you will spread
把你们的知识财富平等的
Your wealth of knowledge equally
教授于所有的住院医生
Among all of the residents.
此外我们还将精力集中于
In addition we will refocus our attention
跟病人的沟通和对病人的礼貌上
On patient communication and bedside manner.
对于我们当中的一些人
For some of us
这意味着去学习一门丢失的艺术  博爱与怜悯
This means learning the lost art of humanity and compassion.
对于其他的一些来说  意味着学会
For others this means leaing how to treat patients
对待病人不要感情用事
Without becoming emotionally involved with them.
谢丽 博登  30岁  四期结肠癌伴随肝转移
Shelley boden 30 stage iv colon cancer with liver mets.
谢丽已经经过化疗和放疗
Shelley has been through extensive chemo and radiation
根据CT显示  如果现在进行肝切除术
And according to the c.t. A liver resection at this point
还可能治愈
Could be curative.
会治愈的  一定会
Will be curative. Will.
你还有什么问题想问我们吗?
Do you have any other questions for us?
如果癌症转移的范围比预想的大怎么办?
What happens if you find More cancer than you expect?
别这样 简
No jenn.
第一这不可能发生  第二
"a " that's not gonna happen and "b  "
你要问的问题伊兹都已经回答了多次了
Izzie's already answered all of your questions three times.
但是伊兹不是主刀医生
Well izzie's not the main surgeon.
伊兹很棒
Izzie's awesome.
我们爱伊兹
We love izzie.
这是格蕾医生  她将协助你们做术前准备
This is dr.Grey. She's gonna prep you for surgery
并且回答你们的问题
And answer any more questions you have.
伊兹不留下?
Izzie's not staying?
这里是外科
This is a surgical program.
精神科在5楼
Psychiatry is on the fifth floor.
撇开这两点不谈
Let's not confuse the two.
还有 对于住院医生来说  实习医生就代表你们
In addition residents your interns reflect on you.
他们失败  你们就失败
If they fail you fail.
他们成功  你们就成功
If they succeed  you succeed.
这些注意事项使用于全部的住院医生
Attendings that goes for residents as well.
用激情去教
Teach with enthusiasm.
用激情去学
Learn with enthusiasm.
因为我们是外科医生
We are surgeons.
我们要治愈病人
We cut out malignancies.
所有的人  此刻此地就行动起来吧
Let's start at home people.
欧麦利
O'malley.
这是班尼特 爱泼斯坦医生
This is Dr.Bennett Epstein
他是你今天考试的监考员
He'll be your proctor for the exam today.
准备好了吗  欧麦利?
You about ready O'malley?
-是的  主任  -你有整整三个小时
-yes sir.-You have exactly three hours
在你开启试卷以后计时
From the moment you open the test.
一旦你打开封条你就不能离开这间屋子
Once you break the seal you may not leave the room
直到你完成全部的考试
Until you have completed the entire exam.
-祝你好运  欧麦利  -谢谢
-Good luck o'malley.-Thank you sir.
我能搞定
I can do this.
我没有结婚  没有背着我老婆
I am not married and cheating on my wife
和我的好友乱搞
With my best friend.
一切事情都在正轨
Everything's just as it should be.
见鬼  破轮椅
Damn chair.
等等  好吧
Hang on.All right.
貌似这个轮椅坏了
Looks like the wheel's broken.
这就是我身边物件的真实写照
That's how things work around me.
我的烤面包机上个月坏了
My toaster broke last month
猫跑了  还有我的后门倒了
Then my cat ran away and my back porch collapsed.
当然电视也只会显示绿色
Also my tv only shows the color green.
我重新找个轮椅去
I'll get another chair.
不用麻烦了  也许我自己走路还更保险
Don't bother I'll walk.probably safer.
不  欧布林先生你必须坐在椅子上
No mr. O'brien you need to stay in chair.
这个是医院的规定  欧布林先生
It's hospital policy.Mr. O'brien!
-我去年也有三次车祸  -欧布林先生
Mr. O'brien.-I've also had three car wrecks In the last year.
谁推个床过来
Somebody get me A gurney over here.
先生  不好意思
Sir i am very sorry.
我撞到头了
I hit my head.
真的是非常非常抱歉
I'm very   very sorry.
去做个CT
Okay get a a c.t.
还有每个小时都要向我汇报他的情况
And i want hourly updates on his condition.
是
Yes, sir.
你不会有事的
You're gonna be okay.
-迈克  天花板漏水了  -可能是水管爆了
- Mike, my ceiling's raining here. - It looks like a pipe burst.
得把这里的水闸关了
We gotta turn off the water and isolate it.
不行  这里是手术层
No, no, this is the surgical floor.
需要有水才能做手术
Water's required to scrub in
才能清洁用具  才能保持病人的生命
to clean equipment, to keep people alive
我要你在不断水的情况下修好它
I need you to fix this with the water on.
-我试试  -那好  随时向我汇报
- I can try. - All right, keep me posted.
主任
Um, chief...
会议室有点漏水了
There is some kind of leak in the conference room.
别和我说这
You don't say.
有没有什么别的地方
I was wondering if there was some--anywhere else
来进行考试
that I could take the exam.
我会自己找个地方的
I will find a different room on my own.
谢谢您
Thank you, sir.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
马克·斯隆发现我们的事了
Mark Sloan has found us out.
马克一开始就知道  我告诉他的
Mark's known from the beginning. I told him.
他可是马克·斯隆啊
He's Mark Sloan.
你就没有可以倾诉事情的对象吗?
Well, you don't have a person that you talk to about things?
你就是那个我倾诉事情的对象
You are the person that I talk to about things.
我不希望我的私事被别人知道
And I like to keep my private life private--
谁都不行  特别是马克...
From everyone，but most definitely from Mark...
斯隆
Sloan.
(房屋出租)
(Apartment For Rent)
手术要多长时间
How long will the operation be?
-至少几个小时  -你觉得还会更久
- At least a couple of hours. - You think it could be longer?
如果出现并发症
If There are complications
或者癌细胞转移更严重的话
or if the mets are more extensive--
-不会的  Jenn  -可如果
- They won't be. Jenn - But what if
简  别这样
Jenn, please stop.
告诉爸妈手术只需要2小时
Just call mom and dad, tell them two hours.
自从我患上癌症
Since I got cancer
我姐姐成天说的只有癌症
My sister's only capable of talking about cancer
这比得癌症更糟
which is so much worse than the cancer.
我知道我不认识你  不过你跟我泄漏点什么吧
So I know I don't know you, but spill.
说什么
Spill what?
随便什么  求你了
Anything, I'm begging you
趁她还没回来叫你
Before she comes back and asks you
详细描述我肝脏的每一块地方
to describe my liver cell by cell.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
你想听我愚蠢的老板的事
Um... do you want to hear about my stupid boss
还是我愚蠢男朋友的事
or my stupid boyfriend.
男朋友  当然是男朋友
Oh, boyfriend. Definitely the boyfriend.
帕特莫先生
Okay, Mr. Patmore.
我会对你进行各种刺激
I'm gonna give you a variety of different stimuli
这样我们就能得到波形图
so we can take a look at the wave patterns generated.
现在我要你把手从眼睛上拿开
I need you to remove your hand from your eyes now.
好  现在还是8级疼痛吗
Okay, are we still at an eight?
还是8级
It's still at eight.
很好
Good. Okay.
开始视觉刺激
Starting visual stimuli.
你要是我  你也会赶他们走
If you were me, you'd want 'em out...
那些室友
the roommates.
我没那么不可理喻吧
I'm not being unreasonable, right?
他的脉搏变弱了
His pulse is coming down.
你必须承认  你会赶他们走的
But you have to admit you'd want them out
你要是我  你也会赶他们走
If you were me, you would want them out.
如果需要做手术的话
If we have to operate
我会让你进行头颅钻孔
I'll let you drill burr holes by yourself.
好吧  我会赶他们走的
Fine, I'd want them out. Whatever.
我就知道
Knew it.
帕特莫先生
Ay, Mr. Patmore.
现在我们要给你换个姿势
Okay, we're gonna change your position now, okay?
杨医生  我有个想法
Um, Dr. Yang, I think I have an idea.
别想  不行
Well, don't think, no
快去实验室把他的测试结果拿来
And run to the lab for his test results.
但伊兹会烤饼干  而阿历克斯会修东西
But Izzie bakes and Alex fixes things.
好吧  当我摆脱癌症以后
Okay, when I am no longer cancer girl
如果我出去遇到个性感的医生
And I can go out and meet a hot doctor
他让我的世界摇摇欲坠  还想搬进来跟我住的话
who rocks my world and wants to move in with me
我也许会放弃饼干和维修服务
I might forgot the baked goods and repair work.
抬头  12点方向
Heads-up, 12:00.
就想让你知道
Just so you know
克里斯蒂娜认为你应该让他们搬走
Cristina thinks you should move them out.
你该跟他谈谈
You should talk to her.
老姐
Dude...
你怎么没提到他的头发
you failed to mention the hair.
是啊  他的头发
Yeah, yeah, the hair.
那是招我喜欢的东西之一
It's one of the many things that makes me happy.
斯隆医生
Dr. Sloan, um
我今天跟着谢博德治疗一个疼痛症病人
I'm working with Shepherd today on a pain patient
我帮乔治学习时读过这篇文章...
And I read this article while I was helping George study...
真可怜
Pathetic.
是  我知道我很可怜
Yes, I know, I'm pathetic.
但我的确读过这篇文章
But I did read this article
而且我记得很清楚
And I do have a photographic memory
主任在推行他的新政策
And the chief's on his new thing
他希望你们能听听实习生的意见
Where he wants the interns to be heard
-而不是视而不见  -少说几句  格蕾
-and not just seen - Use fewer words, Grey.
我觉得他需要一位耳鼻喉科专家
I think he needs an E.N.T.
你是耳鼻喉科的对吧
You're an E.N.T., right?
你觉得怎么样  欧布林先生
How you doing in there, Mr. O'brien?
不算太糟
Could be worse.
我的大脑还没从耳朵里流出来
Could have brain leaking from my ears.
就喜欢你这种精神
That's the spirit.
再过几分钟就好了
It'll only take a couple more minutes.
坚持住
Hang on.
猜我找到什么了  房子
Guess what I found-- an apartment
很漂亮的房子  里面有硬木地板
A beautiful apartment with hardwood floors
还有个很大的壁炉
and an Honest-To-God fireplace
你可以在里边生很大的火
That you can build Honest-To-God fires in
不过我一个人租不起这房子
And I can't afford it by myself.
所以  我想如果你能摆脱过去的不愉快
So... I thought if you could get over yourself
我们可以合租这房子
We could live together.
不  谢了
No, thanks.
我提到硬木地板了吗?
Did I mention the hardwood floors
以及硕大的壁炉
And the honest-To-God fireplace?
我宁愿本本分分的住在我的汽车里
I'd rather live in my Honest-To-God car.
好吧
Right.
他怎么样  克莱夫
How's he doing, Karev?
你觉得我们会面临指控吗
You think we're looking at a lawsuit?
现在我还不清楚  但我觉得不会
Well, we don't have a picture yet, but, uh, No.
这家伙不像是会提出控诉的人
This guy doesn't seem like the lawsuit type.
希望你是对的
Well, let's hope you're right.
有人吗
Hello?
万分抱歉
I cannot apologize enough. Oh.
你给我像照顾至尊一样照顾他
You treat him like a king.
你听到了吗  欧布林先生
You hear that, Mr. O'brien?
-是的  -克莱夫医生会很好的照顾你
- Yeah. - Dr. Karev is gonna take great care of you.
你是我们今天头号重要的病人
You're our number one priority today.
-你还好吗  -上帝讨厌我
- You okay?  - God hates me.
-欧布林先生  我很...  -我妻子离我而去
- Mr. O'brien, I am...  - My wife left me.
我的会计骗走了我的钱
My accountant stole from me.
我工作的地方被烧了
The store I worked at burned down.
我被诊断出有动脉瘤
I was diagnosed with an aneurysm
因此我需要做手术
for which I require surgery
而这个医院又好像
in a hospital that seems to be...
老跟我过不去
crumbling around me.
上帝真的讨厌我
God hates me.
你看这里  剩下的肿瘤很容易就找到了
You can see the remaining tumor is easily identified here.
她的肝脏看上去很健康
Her liver looks so healthy.
这就是普外科的美丽
That's the beauty of general surgery.
你能看见坏的东西被好的东西包围
You see badness surrounded by goodness--
切掉坏的东西  世界就太平了
Cut out the badness, all is right with the world.
就靠你和你的手术刀
It's just you and your scalpel
一对一
One-On-One
单打独斗
Mano a mano.
好吧  我这是在用热情教你
Okay, this is me teaching with enthusiasm.
不
No.
欧麦利
O'malley.
什么?!
What?!
如果你已经完成了测试
Um... if you're finished with your test, um
听着  医院都发水灾了  断层扫描机器坏了
Look, the hospital's flooding, the C.T. is on the fritz
我术后以及术前的病人都耽搁好几天了
My post-Op and pre-Op patients are backed up for days.
我需要在病人发现之前
I gotta get a handle on this thing
处理掉这件事情
before the patients find out
不能让咱们从12名继续往下掉了
And our ranking drops way past 12.
我找到了间又好又安静的房间
I found a nice, quiet room
能让你考试时放松心情
In psych for you to take your exam.
我知道了
Oh, I-I-I see.
你  你去吧
Um, yeah, you--you-- You go ahead.
主任
Chief.
我再当一天你的实习生
I am your intern at least for one more day.
我能帮忙
I can help.
谢博德医生  能说句话吗
Dr. Shepherd, a word.
失陪一会儿  什么事
Excuse me one second. Yes.
你介意我在你病人身上做个快速测试吗
Uh, do you, uh, mind if I run a quick test on your patient?
他身上很痛  马克
He's in a lot of pain, Mark.
-我不认为他需要腹部整形  -是吗  有意思
- I don't think he needs a tummy tuck. - Oh, that's funny.
格蕾医生跟我说了个有趣的想法
No, uh, Dr. Grey came to me with an interesting idea
我跟你不同  我打算
And, uh, unlike you, I'm taking the chief's
遵从主任的新教学规范  所以我听她说了
new teaching protocol seriously, so I listened.
我读到过关于肿胀
Uh, I-I read a thing about swelling
以及筛前神经压迫的文章
And compression of the ethmoid nerve.
我相信如果我们往他鼻子里插根导管
I believe if we were to stick a cottle elevator up his nose--
打断一下  往鼻子里插?
No, I'm--I'm sorry. Up his nose?
如果格蕾医生的想法是对的
If Dr. Grey is on the right track
病人会有反应的
The, uh, patient will let us know.
好的
Okay.
帕特莫先生  我是斯隆医生  整形外科主任
Mr. Patmore i'm dr  Sloan  I'm the head of plastic surgery
耳鼻喉科的专家
And an ear nose and throat specialist
如果您不介意的话  我想做一个检查
I'd like to run a quick test If i can have your permission
我看过16个耳鼻喉大夫了  没人能帮我
I've seen 16 e.n.t.s Not one could help me
放松呼吸
Now breathe normally
我会把它插进去
I'm gonna angle this into here
如果觉得不舒服就告诉我
You let me know when you feel any Pain or anything
疼
That's it!
很疼!  就是  就是那里疼! 我的天!
That's the pain!That's what's causing the pain
天啊  天啊
Oh my god  Oh my god
行了
Okay
前筛骨神经综合症
Anterior ethmoid neurovascular complex
一个简单的中鼻甲部分切除术就搞定了
A simple middle turbinectomy will fix it
除非你还想切开他的脑袋前额
Unless you still want to chop out the front of his brain
干得不错
Nicely done
怎么样
How'd it go?
雪莱
Hi shelley
我们从ct检测中发现情况恶化了
We found that the mets were much more extensive than the c.t. Detected
肿瘤已经扩散及你肝脏后的主动脉
And the main tumor actually extended in and around the major blood vessel
-主动脉  -我们会重新做一轮化疗
Behind the liver  We're just gonna start a new round of chemo
没事的
That's all
我已经跟你的肿瘤专家联系过了
I already have a call into your oncologist
他打来的
Oh  That's him
我马上回来
I'll--i'll be right back
我们会为你止疼
We can manage your pain
很抱歉我们只能做这些
I'm sorry we don't have better news
你对你的室友们有什么打算吗
So did you  Decide what to do about your roommates?
我很抱歉  雪莱
I'm so sorry  shelley
没事的
Come on
说说你热情的男友床上功夫如何棒吧
So how good is the hot boyfriend in bed?
我不知道我们之间怎么了
Look  We don't even know what we are yet
为什么马克·斯隆会知道
So how does mark sloan know?
为什么你会告诉他
Why are you talking to him?
而不是我？
Instead of me?
女士们
Ladies
我有打扰到你们吗?
Am i interrupting?
你来的真是时候
You're timing is perfect
是吗  你要调戏她?
Really? Are you about to feel her up?
住嘴  赶紧住嘴
Stop  You have to stop
-我不能严肃  -她讨厌这样
I can't seriously   she hates it
这就是为什么我不能严肃
That's why i can't
别这样  你的屁屁很痒吗?
Don't  you want a spanking?
是你告诉德里克你认为我会开除他们吗
So you told derek you think I should kick them out?
不  是这样
No  No is
我告诉他我希望他们走人  是我而不是你
I told him i would want them out  me   not you
我只是说因为他不会住嘴
And i only said it 'cause he wouldn't stop talking
所以你认为我不会开除他
So you don't think I should kick them out?
但是我认为我会
'Cause i think i'm going to
我的意思是大家都是成年人  对吗
I mean i think it's the adult thing to do  don't you?
你的精神病医生怎么说
What does your shrink say?
我辞掉了我的精神病医生
I quit my shrink
我很好  我们都很好
I'm happy  We're happy
我能坐在这里吗
Hey   can i sit here?
这边  乔治  事情进展的怎么样?
Hey! George  uh  How--how did it go?
有些漏水问题
I just  There was a water problem
我只是想试着帮帮主任
I mean i'm just trying to help the chief
我甚至不惜忘记所有的医疗案例
Even though all the medical facts are falling out of my ear onto the floor
吃这个吧  这东西对脑子有好处
Eat this  It's brain food
我的动脉瘤病人被水滑倒
My dude with the aneurysm fell in the water
撞到头被送进ct室了
Smacked his head and got stuck in the c.t. Machine
我的病人总是撒谎
My patient's dying
我恨我关心他们的时候他们却在撒谎
I hate it when i like them and they're dying
我们的病人生活在病痛之中
Our guy's been living in pain
在过去的7年里因为鼻炎一直忍受着8级疼痛
Pain at a constant eight for the last seven years because of an inflamed nerve in his nose
-这很荒唐  -我希望我也得鼻炎
That's crazy  I wish i had an inflamed nerve in my nose
没办法  他们已经8级疼痛了
There is no way that that guy has been living at an eight
他是个懦夫  他的八级相当于我的三级  我就能忍受
He's a wimp  His eight My three  I can take pain
你不能跟我的男朋友聊这么长时间
You can't talk to my boyfriend for ten minutes
好吧  痛苦的酷刑
Well  there's pain and then there's torture
我能忍受  狠狠的试试我
And i can take pain  Seriously test me
-一点都不痛  -令人敬佩
Nothing. That's impressive
闭嘴  你只是轻轻的碰了下
Shut up  You barely touched her
-不要  -住手  住手
Ow! No   no  No! Ow! Knock it off! Stop it!
你怎么样判断是不是他神经过敏呢
Um  how did you diagnose that nerve
因为我从来没听说过这种情况
Because i've never even heard of that condition before?
我记得有一片文章
I remembered an article
在<<英国耳鼻喉期刊>>里
From the "british journal Of e.n.t."
是1964年出版的47号19页
And it was issue number 47 Page 19 from 1964
图画纪念版
Photographic memory
-伙计  雷谢斯方法论  -我讨厌你
Dude   lex-opedia  Oh   i hate you
别讨厌我  我能帮到你
Don't hate me  I can help you
主任
Oh   uh   chief
水灾处理得怎么样了?
What's going on with the flood?
这不是水灾  贝利  这只是一个管子（漏了）
It's not a flood   bailey. It's a pipe that...
微乎其微  不用担心
It's minor okay. Not to worry
你不是有个外科手术吗
Aren't you headed to surgery?
是的  主任
Yes   sir
主任  一个月以前
Chief   a few months ago
我家小特科把一个
Little tuck flushed
变形金刚的小手指冲进了马桶
One of his action figures down the toilet
我想那没多大关系
And i thought it was no big deal minor
但我回家进厨房时
But then i came home to a kitchen
厨房已经淹了好几英寸的厕水
Filled with several inches of poop water
厕水
Poop water?
在我的厨房里  主任
In my kitchen   sir
谢谢你  贝利医生  但是这件事情还在控制之内
Thank you  dr. Bailey  But i have this under control
好的  先生
Yes   sir
厕水
Poop water
显然有些裂缝
So apparently there's some kind of leak
头儿让我去把所有准备手术的病人
And the chief wants me
都搬到门诊部
To move all the pre-op patients to the clinic
谁有空帮我
So who's free to help me?
这可不是一个很高的痛点哦
Not a high pain threshold  Huh?
知道不? 把他丢出去  是他  不是我
You know what? Throw him out. Not me  just him
她更喜欢我  我烧饭给大家吃还打扫屋子
She likes me more.I bake for everyone and i clean
你只会带来淫词秽句
The only thing you bring to the house is filth
你是更喜欢梅丽迪斯  巧克力蛋糕  还是s.t.d.?
What would you prefer meredith
水!
Water!
天啊  到处都是水  发生什么了
Oh   god. It's everywhere. What's happening? What happened?
一直向前走
Let's keep moving  Move!
做完手术的送到2415室
Post-ops to rooms 2415
准备做手术的送到 2233,4,5室
Pre-ops to rooms 2233  4 and 5
水漫到门诊室了
The overflow Goes into the clinic
主任
Chief
我来控制住局势
I  i got everything under control up here
你和斯蒂芬去看看门诊室
But i need you to oversee Stevens with the pre-ops
等待手术的病人
In the clinic
主任  也许我们需要闭院
Okay  sir  Maybe we need to shut down
把病人送到仁爱医院和西雅图圣恩医院
Just send the patients to mercy west  seattle pres
管道会被修好
They can repair the pipe
这样我们就能争取时间
And we'll be up and running in no time
我正在送所有病人去没水的地方
I am sending all our patients to dry ground
我关闭了除了两个手术室以外的所有地方
I closed all but two o.r.s
维护部门已经关闭了泄漏的管道
Maintenance has isolated the broken pipe
还是很感谢你  贝利医生
So thank you   dr. Bailey
我说了  一切都在控制之中的时候
But when i say that i've got it under control
-这就是我要说的  -但即使他们关闭了管道
That's what i mean
还是有大量的水已经漏出来了
But a lot of water got out before they did
我想说也许...
I'm just saying that maybe
贝利医生  去诊所!  马上!
Dr. Bailey   clinic   now!
是的  主任  我现在就去
Yes   sir. On my way
慢着点
Hey   hey   slow down
好了  接下来?
Okay   what next?
等等  你确信你有时间搞定这些吗
Wait  Are you sure you have time for this?
-我真希望你能去做你的测试  -谢谢
I really want youTo get to take your test  Thank you
格蕾
Grey
尽管你对男人的品味不咋的
Despite your   uh  unfortunate taste in men
但是你也不是一无是处
It turns out you're not entirely useless
帕特莫尔先生的情况非常罕见
Mr. Patmore's condition is extremely rare
但你抓到了症结
And you nailed it
刷手上台吧
You can scrub in
现在?
Now?
现在你要在发水灾的时候做手术吗
You're doing the surgery now  With the  with the flood?
水灾算不了什么
The flood's contained
而我们的病人已经疼了七年了
And our man's been in pain for seven years
手术台见
See you in surgery
我不行  很抱歉  我现在没空
I can't.  I'm sorry  um  but i'm busy
我正在忙于帮助主任处理一些事情
I'm really busy Helping the chief with the
主任的实习医师
Chief's  um  intern
很谢谢你  但是下次好吗
I  i  thank you  but maybe next time?
不  小姑娘  没有下次了
No   lassie  There won't be a next time
真可惜
Pathetic
帕特摩先生  我只是要抽一点血
Mr. Patmore   i'm just gonna draw some blood
注射一点减充血剂
And   uh   place a topical decongestant
在我带你进手术室前
Before i take you to surgery
当然好的
Absolutely  Of course
你现在疼痛等级多少
How's your pain level now?
8级  一直都是8级
Eight  It's always at eight
看起来你已经好些了
It looked like you had some relief
我已经花了7年时间
I've spent seven years
看了39个医生
I've seen 39 doctors
谢谢
Thank you
我尝试过各种止痛方法
And i've tried every kind of painkiller
都不管用
And nothing helps
有医生告诉我说这是我的幻觉
I've had doctors tell me It's my imagination
说我是脑子出了问题
That i'm crazy
说我是嗜药成瘾
Call me a drug addict
我的妻子去年死了
My wife died last year
在花了好多年陪我
After spending years carting me around
不停的反复的看医生做检查后
To doctor after doctor test after test
她死了
She died
她是我最好的朋友
She was my best friend
她是我最喜欢的人
She was my favorite person.
但是她死了
And she died...
而我没有感觉了
And i couldn't feel it.
我对疼痛没有感觉了
I couldn't feel that pain
因为我脑子里想的都是那件事
Because i was so completely occupied with this one.
而现在我终于知道为什么了
And now i finally know what's wrong
斯隆医生正要给我上麻醉药
And dr. Sloan's gonna fix it.
所以你说的是对的
So you're right.
你说的对 我已经感到好些了
You're right that.  I'm feeling some relief.
好吧  让我来帮你抽血
Okay   let's get your blood drawn.
我不干  我不会做手术的
I'm not gonna do it. I'm not gonna have surgery.
我会受伤害的
It's just gonna hurt.
她要把我切成一半  可能会杀了我
She's gonna slice me in half.And probably kill me.
就算她没杀死我  我也觉得置身地狱
If she doesn't kill me. It'll just hurt like hell.
可能会受感染或者更加疼痛
Probably get infected and hurt worse.
-我不会做手术的  -听着  我知道你很害怕
I'm not gonna do it. Look, I get that you're scared
但是如果你想要活下去  你就得做这个手术
But if you want to live, you need the surgery.
我是不是想活下去?  你有没有在意过?
If i want to live? Have you been paying any attention?
我女朋友怀孕的时候情绪异常激动
My girlfriend had a hysterical pregnancy
她发疯地割脉  虽然我在另一个房间
Went nuts   cut her wrists. While I was in the next room
但我却不得不认罪
And had to be committed.
而现在我的室友想把我赶出去
And now my roommate's planning to make me move out.
除了我现在住的地方去哪里我都没钱交得起押金
I have no money for a deposit anywhere else
可能下周我就无家可归了
So chances are next week i'm homeless.
你说这些想让我觉得好过点吗？
You making stuff up to make me feel better?
听着  你必须要有生存的目标
Look   you must have something to live for.
或者即便是为了某种可能性
Or even just the possibility of something.
小卖部有个女孩
There's a girl at the grocery store.
我一直想对她说你好
I keep meaning to say hello.
结果...
Instead i...
却一直只是问她关于商品的事情
Just keep asking her about the produce.
很好  那么你就应该做这个手术
All right. So you get the surgery.
因为可能你的运气就变好了
'Cause chances are your luck's gonna turn around.
这是科学道理
It's science.
平均法则
It's--it's--
风水轮流转
It's gonna turn around.
轮到你的时候
And when it does...
你就说声你好
You say hello.
我说你好
I say hello.
来点薯片吗?
Chips?
巧克力呢?
Chocolate?
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么了?
What?
你这人还不算太糟
You're not a terrible person.
然后呢
Okay.
我知道我们的看法总是不一致  但是
I know we don't always see eye to eye   but...
我找到这个很棒的公寓
I found this really great apartment.
它就在医院门口的马路对面
It's right across the street from the hospital.
房间的光线很好
It has really great light.
我知道你能承担的起  它是免费提供给伯克
I know you can afford it and it's burke-free.
住他的老地方当然很糟
It must be kind of awful living in his old place.
不过考虑一下吧
Think about it.
你可以更多的打开些牵引器
You can open that retractor up a little more
如果你想看的更清楚的话
If you want to get a better look.
只要保证别把小肠弄出来就行了
Just make sure you keep the small bowel inside.
-我们不想引起肠梗阻  -我们更不想
-We want to avoid a post-op ileus. -Well, we better.
这家伙觉得自己是个扫把星
The dude thinks there's a dark cloud following him around.
这听上去太戏剧化了
Well   that sounds overly dramatic.
那是什么?
What's that?
那个
What's
到底是什么?
What the hell?
喂!  喂!
Hey hey.
喂!  快点转移
Hey   mo-move
-转移病人  -什么?
-Move the patient. -What?
转移病人!
Move the patient!
我的天!
Oh my god!
大家都还好吗?  我们的病人怎么样?
Is everyone okay? How's our patient?
他情况稳定  生命体征稳定
He's stable. Vitals holding steady.
-好 冲洗  -我能帮什么忙?
-All right.Irrigation, please. -How can i help?
去找主任然后告诉他发生了什么
Find the chief and tell him what happened.
-我们另需一个手术室  -其他手术室都被关了
-God   we need a new o.r. -They shut down all the other O.r.s except for this one
还有斯隆医生的  克莱夫  去斯隆医生那边
And dr. Sloan's.Okay uh karev Go to sloan.
他刚开始手术  也许还能关闭手术室
He just got started. Maybe he can close.
好吧  我需要大家的帮忙
All right. I need everybody's help.
-我们要转移 欧布林先生 -我跟斯隆怎么说?
-We're gonna get ready to move Mr. O'brien. -What do i tell sloan?
就说这天杀的天花板掉下来了
Just tell him the damn sky is falling.
鼻镜和麻醉剂
Nasal speculum and lidocaine.
鼻镜太大了  再给我支麻醉
Larger speculum. Another lidocaine.
我们就光看着?
We're just watching?
我是疼痛专家
I'm a pain specialist
我可不要错过这个
And i would've missed this thing.
所以没错  我们就只是看着
So yes. We're just gonna watch.
别再利用我来试探和影响她
Don't ever use me again to try and influence her.
你和我可不是一组 梅丽迪斯...
You and I are not team. Meredith...
我们需要一个手术室
We need the o.r.
我们需要一个手术室!
We need the o.r.!
塌在病人身上?
On a patient?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
倒塌?
Collapsed?
你的员工没受伤
Your staff wasn't hurt.
但是病人的腹部敞开着
But the patient's abdomen was open.
据我了解  他现在没事了
He's stable as far as i know.
贝利医生  传我的话
Dr. Bailey, spread the word.
我们将关闭外科楼层
We are closing the surgical floor.
并把我们的病人转移
And shipping our patients out
-去仁爱医院和西雅图圣恩医院  -是的  先生
-To mercy west and seattle presbyterian. -Yes, sir.
贝利医生...
And dr. Bailey...
出去的时候别幸灾乐祸
Try not to gloat on the way out.
没有幸灾乐祸  先生
No gloating, sir.
-你们还看到哪里有受伤出血吗?  -没有  没有了
-Anybody see any more damage any bleeding? -No,no bleeding.
-我刚刚清除了左下象限  -给我脉冲灌注器
-I just cleared the lower left quadrant. -Give me the pulse irrigator.
汉娜医生
Dr. Hahn
看一下这边  就这里
Take a look at this. Right here.
胰腺  是不是碎片造成的损伤?
The pancreas--is that Uh damage from the debris?
不  不是
No, no.
那是个瘤
That's a tumor.
他妈的
Son of a bitch.
你是那个心理医生对吧?
You're the shrink right?
是的
Yeah.
你不能让她离开
Well you can't let her quit.
让我猜一下  你是克里斯蒂娜?
Let me guess. Cristina?
她说...不管怎样
She talks ab...Whatever.
你不能让她离开
Um   you can't let her quit
因为我劝不动她了
Because i'm no longer allowed an opinion
因为我是她的死党
Because i'm being supportive.
所以你是我最后的希望
So... You're my last hope.
你必须劝阻她  这是你的职责
I mean  it's your job to have an opinion right?
你不是收了钱来给她忠告的吗?
You're paid to have an opinion?
没错
That's right.
好的
Okay so um...
她活在疼痛度为八级的日子中
She lives her life at an eight.
她的疼痛
Her pain...
不管是哪一天 都高达8级
On any given day she lives at an eight.
而且他却不明白
And he doesn't get that.
他搬了进来  然后希望她...
I mean   he moves in and expects her to--
赶走她的室友
To move her roommas out
你应该看到他不能完全占有她
Which goes to show you how completely he doesn't get her
因为她需要她的室友们
Because she needs them.
所以你得叫她别赶室友们走
So you need to tell her not to move them out.
这尽管不是什么长久之计
I mean it's not gonna work out in the long run anyway
但是她误以为自己很幸福
And she thinks that she's happy but she's not.
而你的本职就是告诉她
And it's your job to tell her.
你一定感到很揪心吧
It must be incredibly painful for you--
因为你的这番说法会让德里克失去梅瑞狄斯
The idea of losing meredith to derek.
你这心理医生糟透了
You're a terrible shrink.
-刚刚和一个肿瘤专家谈过  -不
-Just talk to the oncologist. -No.
那边有个临床试验
There's a clinical trial
-他们用化疗加上阿瓦斯丁  -你不是医生
-Using chemo plus avastin. -And there's...You're not a doctor.
请不要以医生的口吻说话
Please stop talking like you're a doctor.
你好
Hello.
你刚才呼叫我了吗?
Did you have me paged?
是的  因为...
Yes because...
我快要死了  在我死之前
I'm dying and you can't let me die
我得知道你的选择
Without knowing what you decided.
不  他们在她的肝脏下面找到了肿瘤
No they found mets underneath her liver.
你看上去很严肃
You look very serious.
我的天
Oh my god.
你会和他分手吗?
Are you gonna break up with him?
不公平
No fair.
我快要死了  而你正在经历轰轰烈烈的爱情抉择
I'm dying and you're casting all that hotness in the wind.
不公平
No fair.
这不公平
It's no fair.
不公平  不公平  不公平
No fair   no fair   no fair.
过一会儿
Dr. Hahn's gonna come in and talk to you
汉娜医生会进来和你谈
In a couple of minutes.
情况怎样了?  没事吧?
How'd it go? Okay?
事实上并不怎么好
Actuallynot so okay.
水灾损坏了手术室的天花板
The flood weakened the ceiling in the o.r.
天花板倒塌成碎片
The ceiling collapsed in several fragments
那些碎片进入了你的切口
Landed inside your incision.
由于那些天花板碎片  我们不得不进一步查看你的腹部
Because of the ceiling thing we had to explore your abdomen
比原来更加彻底地仔细查看
More thoroughly than we normally would have
而结果...
And... As a result
我们发现你的胰腺上有个恶性肿瘤
We found a malignant tumor on your pancreas.
癌症?  你们发现癌症了?
Cancer? You found cancer?
等等
Wait wait!
听着  听我说  是这样的
Listen, listen to me 'cause here's the thing
我们取了样本  做了化验
We took it out. We sent it to pathology.
-仅仅是一期而已  -只是一期
-It was only stage 1.  -Only stage 1
我们从未这么早发现胰腺癌
We never find pancreatic fumors so early.
这病在发现后
They're always a death sentence
一般都回天乏术
by the time they're diagnosed
但你却不是
But not for you
我们把整个肿瘤都摘除了
We took the tumor, the whole thing.
全都取出来了  甚至都不用做化疗
We took it out. You won't even need chemo.
天花板掉下来了
That ceiling collapse
但却救了一你命
It saved your life.
你时来运转了  好运来了
Your luck has turned, man.  It's turned
我想对那个女孩...  说声你好
I'm gonna say hello... to that girl.
我想说声你好
I'm gonna say hello
主任
Chief
Chief?
主任  我把所有病人的研究资料
Chief I've downloaded
和X光片影像都写进DVD里了
all our patients labs and radiology onto DVDs
并把它们存入相应的档案里了
And I've attached them to each of their charts.
还有什么可以帮忙的吗
Is there anything else I can do to help?
情况怎样?
How'd it go?
我知道  我很可悲
I-I know. I'm pathetic
乔治也并不知道我退出了
and George doesn't know I exist.
我还错过了手术  和其他甚多要事
And I missed my surgery and BLAH BLAH BLAH.
快告诉我帕特莫先生的手术
Could you please just tell me how it went
-进行得如何  -我们没完成手术
-with Mr. Patmore?  -We didn't get to do the surgery
帕特莫先生被转移到另一家医院去了
Mr. Patmore has been shipped off to another hospital
在明天之前  他应该不会感到疼痛
and he will be out of pain by this time tomorrow
-有过目不忘的记忆力  是吗  -是的
-photographic memory huh?  -yeah
元素周期表  开始
Periodic table. go.
氢  氦  锂  铍  硼  碳
Hydrogen Helium Lithium Beryllium Boron Carbon
氮  氧  氟  氖  钠  镁
Nitrogen Oxygen Fluorine Neon Sodium Magnesium
铝  硅  磷  硫
Aluminum Silicon Phosphorus Sulfur
我还能继续讲
I can keep going.
-壁炉居然还能烧真木  -看到没  这点我最喜欢
-We could burn actual wood?  -See? That's my favorite part
-你不可能找到更好的了  -瞧这里  真是太棒了
-You can't find that anymore.  -Look at this. It's gorgeous
你们觉得怎样
What do you think?
谢谢  这套公寓真是太棒了
Thank you! This is a fantastic apartment.
-我们非常喜欢  -绝对喜欢  喜欢  喜欢
-We totally love it.  -Love it, Love it.
你真是太好了  伊兹  真的  谢谢
It was really great of you, Izzie. Really, thank you.
你在开玩笑  是吧
You're kidding, right?
你是不是在开玩笑
克里斯蒂娜  你在耍我吗
Cristina, are you kidding me?
我从我房子里被人赶了出来
I'm getting kicked out of my house
你觉得我是为你从板上扯下这张广告的
You think I pulled this off the board for you?!
我是邀请你跟我一起住
I was asking you to live there with me
哦  对不起
Oh Uh... I'm sorry.
-哦  是啊  -我真的很...  哇哦  这下可热闹了
-Oh, yeah.  -I'm so... wow, huh? Hilarious.
-但  我很抱歉...  -我...我还是去吧台好了
-But no.  I'm sorry.  -I...I'm getting into the bar.
知道吗  你...  快把传单还给我
You know what?  You just...give me the flyer
我已经下了定金了
um... I already put a deposit down.
真是不好意思  你应该说清楚啊
I'm sorry. I mean, You should've been more clear.
好  你知道吗  好的  你留着吧
Fine. You know what? it's fine. Keep it.
-完全没问题  好好享受吧  -谢谢
-That's totally fine. Enjoy, that's fine!  -Thank you
我明白了  你很注重个人隐私
I get that you're a private person
但我不是  我喜欢与别人分享
But I am not. I process my stuff out loud
我为了婚姻  放弃了太多
And I gave up too much of myself in my marriage.
我不能因此再放弃自我
I can't... give up pieces of myself again.
而马克是我的朋友
and Mark is my friend.
我想我恨他  是因为他见过你裸体
I think I just hate him because He's seen you naked
这究竟是怎么了?
What was the point?
所有的时光和所有的金钱  究竟是怎么了?
All those hours and all that money.  What's the point?
这世界真是可怕
The world is a horrible place.
年轻人因疾病而死亡
Young people die of diseases.
完全没有必要装得很高兴
It makes absolutely no sense to try to be happy
-总之  这是个可怕的世界  -没错
-In a world, that's such a horrible place.  -Yes.
-什么意思?  -是的  可怕的事经常发生
-What?  -Yes, horrible things do happen
因此而把高兴装在脸上
Happiness in the face of all of that
这并不是目的
That's not the goal.
感觉可怕
Feeling the horrible
并勇于感知  你不会因这种恐惧而死
And knowing that you're not gonna die from those feelings
那才是重点
That's the point
你还没完蛋
And you're not done.
你把你对恐惧的感觉
You've made progress
告诉了我  并选择开始治疗
because you're feeling and you're telling me about it.
6个月前
6 months ago
你仅仅只和酒在打交道
It would've been just you and a bottle of tequila.
我的大门始终向你敞开
my door is always open.
骨折
bones break...
器官破裂
organs burst...
皮肉撕破
flesh tears...
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
我为你高兴
You know, I'm happy for you
我为你和德里克感到高兴
I am. I'm really happy for you and Dereck
你们马上要搬到一起住了
and that you guys are moving forward.
我不知为何  我没有知心的人
I don't know how it happened that I don't have anyone
我没有任何闺密
but... I don't have anyone
不是这样的  伊兹
That's not true, izzie
并非如此
It's not true.
你们好
hello
我们能缝合伤口
We can slew the flesh
修补创伤
repair the damage
减轻痛楚
ease the pain.
我发现了你老妈的陈年马爹利
I found your mom's vintage martini set.
你怎能自以为  我会把他们赶出去
You can't just assume I'm gonna kick my family out.
你不应该越过我  向他们宣布此事
And you don't get to announce it to them and ambush me
你更不能把克里斯蒂娜收拢到你这边来
you definitely don't get to try to get cristina on your side
他们是我的家人  你和他们  都是我的一切
They're my family. They're who I have, you and them.
好吧
Okay
好的
OK?
我可以等你准备好了  再来商谈此事
I'd like to talk about it again when you're ready.
就现在而言  没问题
But for now, Okay.
那你还爱我吗?
So you still love me?
当生活停顿下来
But when life breaks down...
梅丽迪斯
Meridith...
当我们停顿下来
When we break down...
是的
Yes.
就再也没有科学  真理和白金法则
There's no science no hard and fast rules
我们只需感知生命的里程
We just have to feel our way through
对于外科医生而言  没什么可以更糟
and to a surgeon there's nothing worse
也没什么可以更好
and there's nothing better.
你确定要这么做吗  主任  你今天够累的了
You sure about this, Sir?  You've had a long day.
站在台上演讲相当容易
It's one thing to stand on a stage and give a speech.
倘若要提高我们的教学水平
But if I want our teaching program to be the best
当然我致力于此
And I do
就必须从这里开始  由我亲自带头
Then it starts here. And it starts with me.
对于大水我无能为力
I can't do anything about the flood.
但我可以把机会留给你  欧麦利
But I can give you your shot, O'Malley.
你应得的  准备好了吗
You earned it. You ready?
是的  主任
Yes, Sir.
好吧
OK.
你有3小时  开始
You get 3 hours, go